Well then, shall we get right to it?
（サソリ）さて…
（サソリ）もうやるか
Here it comes!
（春野はるのサクラ）来る
（サクラ）うっ
（チヨの掛け声）
（サクラ）ああっ…
死ね！
Die!
He's fast!
（チヨ）速い
To think that Hiruko's tail
fell to pieces...
ヒルコの尾が バラバラとは
You've got some pretty good moves,\Granny Chiyo.
やるな チヨバア
In that case, how about this?
なら これでどうだ
Oh no!
（チヨ）いかん！
（サソリ）そらあ！
Take this!
With the old lady manipulating things,
it's impossible to get anywhere.
（サソリ）ババアが操ってんなら
らちが明かねえ
（サクラ）あっ
In that case...
だったら…
（サクラ）あっ
（チヨ）いかん！
Oh, no! Sakura! Hold your breath!
サクラ 息を止めろ！
Is it poison?!
（サクラ）毒…
Sakura--!
サクラ！
（デイダラ）
そろそろやるか うん
I guess it's about time to start...
Hold it, damn you!
（うずまきナルト）
待てってばよ こらあ！
How lucky of me...
to take on two Jinchuriki...
（デイダラ）おいらもついてる
２匹も人柱力をやれるとは
（ナルト）うっ
Damn!
（ナルト）クソ！
Naruto!
（はたけカカシ）ナルト！
うっ… はあ
I'm not about to let him get away!
逃がすか！
うっ
くっ…
（カカシ）うっ はっ
カ… カカシ先生！
Kakashi-sensei!
Against a Copy Ninja,
（デイダラ）
さすがに コピー忍者相手には
I guess one Detonating Clay
is a little pathetic...
起爆粘土１つじゃ
お粗末だったな うん
Having said that,
there's only a little Detonating Clay left.
かといって
起爆粘土も残りわずかだ
I was intending to only lure out
the Jinchuriki, but...
人柱力じんちゅうりき１人を
おびき出すつもりだったが
This is troublesome...
こりゃ やっかいだな うん
この… 待ちやがれ！
You jerk... wait!
Wait, Naruto!
（カカシ）待て ナルト！
チッ
We've moved too far away
from Sakura and the others.
（カカシ）
サクラたちから 離れすぎたな
If we move even further away,
the radio transmission will...
しかも これ以上離れると無線が…
I won't be able to contact Guy's group...
ガイ班と連絡が取れなくなる
We better hurry...
急がないと
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Chiyo's Secret Skills
（マイト･ガイ）まだまだ
You ain't seen nothing yet!
（ガイ）おりゃあ
そりゃあ
とっ… クソ…
Damn...
There'll be no end to it this way...
これでは切りがない
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ハア…
ハア！ タア！
Rotation!
回天かいてん！
Damn...
What should I do?
クソ… どうすればいい
（テンテン）はっ
（テンテン）自分と戦うなんて
一体どうすればいいの
Fighting against yourself...
What the hell should I do?
Leaf... Hurricane.
（ロック･リー）木こノ葉は旋風せんぷう
ハア ハア…
I'm really starting to get tired...
いいかげん… 疲れてきました
This poison will kill that girl for sure...
（サソリ）
小娘は この毒で確実に死ぬ
（サクラ）うっ…
I'm okay!
I managed not to inhale it...
（サクラ）大丈夫
なんとか吸い込まずにすんだ
Sakura!
サクラ
させるか
You think I'll let you do that!
フン！
（サソリ）フフッ
くっ うくっ…
Th-This is...!
こ… これは
It's a Kunai Knife with a rope attached.
ロープ付きクナイだ
You should have repelled it,
rather than dodge it, eh?
かわすんじゃなく
はじき返すんだったな
I can't hold my breath...
（サクラ）息が続かない
Sakura!
（チヨ）サクラ…
（サソリ）フッフフ…
So you're determined not
to let Sakura go, are you?
どうあっても サクラを逃さぬ気か
It's useless, Grandma Chiyo.
ムダだ チヨバア
The poison will kill you by inhaling it
even with the slightest dose.
この毒はちょっと吸い込んだだけで
死に至る
（チヨ）サクラ
Sakura...
フッ 終わったな
Looks like it's over...
Naruto...
（サクラ）ナルト
I'm sorry, Naruto...
（サクラ）ごめんナルト
少し待たせることになっちゃうけど
It'll mean I'll keep you waiting a little,
but I promise
今度は きっと…
I won't be a burden next time...
足手まといには ならないから
I promised Naruto...
（サクラ）ナルトと約束したんだ
that this time I wouldn't
be a burden...
今度は 足手まといにならないって
誓ったんだ
I promised him that... this time...
今度は 私が２人を守るって
I would protect the two of them...
I... can't... in a place like this!
私は こんなところで…
The poisonous smoke
will stop in a minute...
（チヨ）もうすぐ毒煙は止まる
Hang in there, Sakura!
持ちこたえてくれ サクラ
フッ…
I didn't plant only one source
of poisonous smoke...
毒煙の仕込みは
１つだけじゃねえぜ
What?!
（チヨ）何！
Sakura! Hold on!
サクラ 待っておれ！
I... can't die...
（サクラ）
私は こんなところで死ねない
in a place like this!
ん？
何？
What!
（チヨ）サクラ！
Sakura!
サクラ しっかりせい
Sakura, hang in there... Sakura!
サクラ！
（サソリ）へ～え
やるじゃねえか
Not bad...
こりゃ いかん
This is bad! She's not breathing!
息をしとらん
Are you all right, Sakura?
ああ 大丈夫か？ サクラ
（サクラ）はい
Y-Yes...
（チヨ）こヤツ
She...
起爆札の爆風で
毒煙を吹き飛ばしたのか？
Did she use the blast waves
of a Paper Bomb
to blow off the poisonous smoke?
しかも ワナから抜けるため自分ごと
Along with herself in it,
escaping the trap in the process...
How reckless of her...!
なんという ムチャを
あんたは…
You...!
あんたは 私が捕まえる！
I will capture you!
うっ… 手足が吹っ飛ぼうが
Even if my arms and legs
were to be blown off...
Even if I were to swallow poison
and become immobile...
毒をくらって動けなくなろうが
必ず捕まえる！
I will capture you, no matter what!
No matter how much
you might resist...
どんなに抵抗されようと
No matter what tricks
you come up with...
どんな手を使われても
私が絶対に大蛇丸おろちまるのことを
吐かせてやる
I will make you tell me everything
about Orochimaru!
いいか！
You hear me?!
（デイダラ）
人柱力をやるとは言ったものの
Even though I said
I'd take the Jinchuriki,
the Copy Ninja is a nuisance.
やっぱ コピー忍者は邪魔だな
I have to somehow separate
him from the Jinchuriki.
なんとか人柱力から
ヤツを引き離さなきゃな うん
（カカシ）ん？
（ナルト）あっ
うっ カカシ先生！
Kakashi-sensei!
ハッ さっすが！
Awesome!
（カカシ）ヤツはなんとかして
That guy is trying by
any means possible
to separate me from Naruto...
俺から ナルトを
引き離そうとしてるな
なるほどな
I see... So he's trying to go
against Naruto one-on-one.
ナルトと差しで
やり合おうってわけだ
ちぇっ 作戦は失敗か
Damn! So my strategy failed, huh.
I guess my only choice is to
target the two of them together.
やっぱ ２人一緒のところを
狙うしかねえか
起爆粘土も 残り少ねえし
I only have
a little Detonating Clay left...
こうなるんなら さっきのアジトに
If I knew it was gonna come to this,
I should have prepared
some more Detonating Clay
もっと起爆粘土の予備を
用意しておくんだった うん
back at the base...
Well, I do have a trump card...
まあ 奥の手はとってあるがな
（サクラ）あっ… えっ
Huh?!
女がしゃべってるときは
男は静かに聞いてやるもんじゃ
When a woman is talking,
a man should listen quietly.
あっ…
ああ… それか
Oh... those things...
（チヨ）覚えておったか
So you remember these, huh...
ああ 一応はな
Yeah, I guess...
（チヨ）そうじゃ
That's right...
お前が作った最初の傀儡くぐつ
They're the first puppets
you ever made.
父ちちと…
The father and...
母ははじゃ
the mother.
Father and mother?
“父と母”
You mean, Sasori's...
じゃあ サソリの
いまさら そんなので
何しようってんだ
So what do you plan to do
with those now, huh?
俺の作った傀儡だ
手の内はバレバレだぜ
Those are puppets I made.
I already know its tricks.
くだらねえ
This is stupid...
果たしてそうかのう
I wonder about that...
（サクラ）ワイヤー？
A wire?
サクラ 下がっておれ
Sakura! Stand back!
はい
Okay!
ハッ！
あっ… すごい
Amazing...
（サソリ）
さすがに面倒になってきたな
This is getting messy.
さっさと これ使うか
I better hurry up and
use this thing...
あっ…
ん…
As I thought, that puppet...
やはり その傀儡
三代目の術を
uses the Third's Jutsu!
久しぶりだろ
You haven't seen this in a while,
have you...?
この術で三代目風影かぜかげは
最強とうたわれたんだからな
This Jutsu is why the Third Kazekage
was praised as the most powerful.
２人とも ぐちゃぐちゃだぜ
I'm gonna turn you guys into mush.
一体 何？
What the hell is that?
あれは 砂隠すながくれで
最も恐れられた武器
That was the most feared weapon
of the Village Hidden in the Sand.
砂鉄さてつじゃ
The Iron Sand.
♪～
Just like always.
daitai itsumo doori ni
As I turn that corner.
sono kado wo magareba
I am lost in the waves of people.
hitonami ni magire komi
Melting, disappearing.
tokete kiete iku
I lose my way.
boku wa michi wo nakushi
I even completely lose my words.
kotoba suranaku shite shimau
But just one thing.
dakedo hitotsu dake wa
Remained, remained.
nokotteta nokotteta
Your voice.
kimi no koe ga
Your smiling faces, your angry faces, everything.
warau kao mo okaru kao mo subete
Keeps me walking on.
boku wo arukaseru
Surely, when I see the point where the clouds have broken.
kumo ga kireta saki wo mitara kitto nee
You know what I mean?
wakaru desho
nee wakaru desho
～♪
Next Episode
むか～し昔 ある里に
Once upon a time,
there was a village in
where a boy lived.
燃えるように赤い髪をした
玉のようにかわいい男の子が…
He was as cute as a button
and had flaming red hair...
きびだんご持って
鬼退治に出かけんだな
Who took millet dumplings along
as he set out to kill the ogres, right!
何言ってんの
まさかり担いで出かける話でしょ
What are you talking about?
The story goes:
"He headed out shouldering a broad axe".
あっ そうだった
Oh, yeah, that's right.
いやいや 両親と
仲よく暮らしておったのよ
Wrong, wrong.
He lived happily with his parents.
で 亀とか助けんのか？
And, rescued a turtle or something?
全然 違うわよ
Not even close.
え～い やめたやめた
Huh, I quit, I quit.
なんの話をしてるのか
分からなくなってしまったわい
I don't even know what story
I was talking about anymore.
（ナルト･サクラ）え～！
- Huh? What happens next? - Huh? What happens next?
続きは？
Father and Mother
Next time: "Father and Mother"
次回「父と母」
NINJA ACADEMY
SPECIAL CLASS
Hi, everybody.
Today I'm gonna tell you...
（カカシ）やあ みんな
きょうは
木ノ葉の師弟関係についてだ
about the Leaf's successive master
and pupil relationships.
First of all, the founder of the Leaf,
まずは 木ノ葉の創始者
初代火影ほかげ様
the First Hokage Lord, and his younger brother,
the Second...
その弟 二代目
Thereafter, the successor to
the Will of the Fire was...
火の意志を受け継いだ三代目
the Third.
The pupils of the Third are
the Legendary Sannin.
そして その三代目の教え子が
Namely, Jiraiya-sama,
Tsunade-sama, and Orochimaru.
伝説の三忍こと
自来也じらいや様 綱手つなで様 大蛇丸だ
綱手様からは シズネが
From Tsunade-sama came Shizune,
from Orochimaru came Mitarashi Anko,
大蛇丸からは みたらしアンコが
自来也様からは四代目が
and from Jiraiya-sama came
the Fourth.
それぞれ教えを受けた
Thus, they each developed
their own talented pupils.
で 四代目の教え子が この俺
And the Fourth Hokage's pupil...
is me, Hatake Kakashi.
はたけカカシ というわけだ
そして これが
俺のかわいい教え子たち
And these are my own dear pupils:
Naruto, Sasuke and Sakura.
ナルト サスケ サクラだ
とはいっても
サクラは 綱手様に弟子入りし
Having said that, Sakura became
a disciple of Tsunade-sama.
Naruto learned various things
from Jiraiya-sama.
ナルトも 自来也様に
いろいろ教わっている
サスケは 里を出たっきり
なんの音沙汰もなし
And Sasuke left the village and
hasn't been heard from since.
It kind of makes me a bit lonely...
（カカシ）
ちょっと さみしいねえ
Ah, you over there.
あっ そこの君
If you'd like, I'll be your teacher...
I'll give you a good rate.
よかったら
俺が先生やってあげようか
サービスしとくよ